<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on MAUPP</title>
    <link>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on MAUPP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Séminaire sur les évolutions sanitaires à Dakar</title>
      <link>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/assess-maupp-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/assess-maupp-seminar/</guid>
      <description>Améliorer les statistiques de décès pour mieux suivre les évolutions sanitaires dans la region de Dakar Le 10 septembre 2019 à Dakar, Sénégal.
Ce séminaire présentera les résultats à mi-parcours du projet ASSESS visant à fournir aux autorités sénégalaises et autres acteurs de développement des informations désagrégées et contextualisées sur les décès et leurs principales causes à Dakar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop en télédétection et cartographie urbaine</title>
      <link>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/assess-maupp-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/assess-maupp-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Modéliser la distribution de la population pour la planification urbaine et la gestion des risques sanitaires Le 9 septembre 2019 à Dakar, Sénégal.
Ce workshop exposera les résultats du projet de recherche MAUPP visant à améliorer notre compréhension et nos prévisions spatiales de l&amp;rsquo;urbanisation et de la répartition de la population urbaine en Afrique grâce à l&amp;rsquo;utilisation de la télédétection et de la modélisation spatiale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IGARSS 2018</title>
      <link>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/igarss2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 01:33:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/igarss2018/</guid>
      <description>The MAUPP team will be present at the IGARSS conference in Valencia, July 22-27, 2018. Two papers were accepted for oral presentation in the session &amp;ldquo;Big Earth Data for Global Scale Applications II&amp;rdquo;:
 Forget, Y., Shimoni, M., Lopez, J-F., Linard, C., Gilbert, M. “Fusion Scheme for Automatic and Large-Scaled Built-up Mapping”. Steele, J.E., Nieves, J., Tatem, A.J., Forget, Y., Shimoni, M., Linard, C. “WorldPop - Fusion of Earth and Big Data for Intraurban Population Mapping”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New paper!</title>
      <link>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/paper-grippa2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/paper-grippa2017/</guid>
      <description>New MAUPP paper on a local segmentation parameter optimization approach:
A local segmentation parameter optimization approach for mapping heterogeneous urban environments using VHR imagery
Taïs Grippa, Stefanos Georganos, Moritz Lennert, Sabine Vanhuysse and Eléonore Wolff
In SPIE Remote Sensing, Warsaw, 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop at ICUH 2017</title>
      <link>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/icuh2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/icuh2017/</guid>
      <description>The MAUPP team organized a pre-conference workshop at the International Conference on Urban Health (ICUH 2017) in Coimbra, Portugal in September 2017. The workshop entitled &amp;ldquo;Human population patterns in sub-Saharan African cities: data and tools for urban health assessments&amp;rdquo; aimed to demonstrate the potentialities of newly developed data and methods in the field of urban population mapping and modelling for urban health decision making. Our broader objective was to meet potential users of our datasets in order to better design them to user needs and understand user learning requirements to inform our capacity building activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Risk Forum</title>
      <link>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/risk-forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 01:41:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/risk-forum/</guid>
      <description>Catherine participated to the 2016 Understanding Risk Forum in Venezia (Italy) on May 16-20, 2016. She was speaker in a session on &amp;lsquo;Building a less risky future: how today&amp;rsquo;s decisions shape disaster risk in the cities of tomorrow&amp;rsquo; organized by GFDRR &amp;amp; Stanford University. Her presentation was entitled &amp;lsquo;Modelling and forecasting urban population patterns for vulnerability assessment&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JURSE 2017</title>
      <link>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/jurse2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 01:33:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/jurse2017/</guid>
      <description>The MAUPP team will be well represented at the Joint Urban Remote Sensing Event (JURSE 2017) that will take place in Dubai, UAE, on March 6-8, 2017. Within a special session on &amp;lsquo;Urban remote sensing for sub-Saharan Africa&amp;rsquo; organized by Michal Shimoni and Eléonore Wolff, three papers from the MAUPP team will be presented:
 Vanhuysse, S., Grippa, T., Lennert, M., Wolff, E., Idrissa, M “Contribution of nDSM derived from VHR stereo imagery to urban land-cover mapping in Sub-Saharan Africa”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Land Project third Open Science Meeting</title>
      <link>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/global-land-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 01:33:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/global-land-project/</guid>
      <description>Catherine participated to the Global Land Project third Open Science Meeting (GLP-OSM) in Beijing, China, October 24-27, 2016. She organized a session with two WorldPop colleagues on &amp;lsquo;Global High Resolution Population Denominators and Urban Spatial Dynamics&amp;rsquo;. The session was very well attended and included seven different talks that ranged from the methodological aspects of global population datasets to the quantification and implications of remote-sensing derived measures of land cover, specifically urban systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GEOBIA 2016</title>
      <link>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/geobia2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 01:32:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/geobia2016/</guid>
      <description>The MAUPP project will be present at the GEOBIA 2016 conference for an oral presentation.
http://maupp.ulb.ac.be/geobia_2016</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From urban mapping to population modelling: current challenges and opportunities</title>
      <link>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/seminar2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 01:33:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/seminar2015/</guid>
      <description>Public seminar This seminar is organized by the MAUPP project, and funded by the BELSPO STEREO III Program.
## Practical informations
The event will take place on 13th January 2015, between 2 and 6 PM, at the Salle Solvay, Building NO, 5th floor (Campus de la Plaine, ULB - 1050 Brussels).
Registration is free, but the number of seats is limited.
An access map is available on the ULB website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The WorldPop team is getting bigger!</title>
      <link>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/worldpop-team-bigger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 01:32:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yannforget.github.io/maupp-website/news/worldpop-team-bigger/</guid>
      <description>Catherine and Yann participated to a WorldPop project meeting in Southampton on October 1st - 2nd, 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>